Rio II《里约大冒险2》2014
Sync & Encoded by Owen Lee
看电影学英语 看美剧学英语
智能手机、IPAD、MP4学英语，请观注：
=-www.en580.com-=『英语我帮您』
《What Is Love》
What is love If it's not with you
I know when you're alone you feel it too
In your arms is where I long to be
Cause being with you gives me sanity
oh...Listen to me darling
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
I wonder if you know it
And what good is the party If you're not around
Listen to me now
What good is love
If it's not your love
This's a crazy party, I'm so glad to be with everybody
Balance with your body,shake it to the ground
Me?
What's a song If you can't heart it too
Can't imagine dancing without Jewel/you!(双关)
A shooting star, ain't really not to see
Cannot write it, he’s standing next to me
Oh....Listen to me darling
I wake up every morning Thinking bout the way you feel
I wonder if you know it And what good is the party
If you're not around Listen to me now
What good is love
If it's not your love
For a bird from Minnesota you've got some moves
明尼苏达州来的鸟还有自己的舞步
Oh, that wasn't a move,that was an accident.
这不是舞步 这是事故
But I accept the compliment.
不过我接受你的恭维
It's great Rafael watch the kids.
多亏拉斐尔能帮我们照顾孩子
Yeah, it Looks like you'll stuck with me...all night.
是啊，这样今天你得和我在一起..一整晚
You are one of my only Blu.
你是我的唯一 布鲁
Ah,that's a good thing, since I am the the only other one.
那太好了，因为公的就剩我一个了（...汗!!!）
- Hi, lovebirds, happy new year! - Rafa, where are...
-比翼鸟 新年快乐 -拉斐尔 他们在哪？
The kids are with Luiz.No worries!
孩子们和路易兹在一起 不用担心！
Worries, right here.
担心？我们很担心
- Luiz, where are the kids? - What? I don't have any kids.
-路易兹 孩子们呢？-什么？我又没有孩子
Our Kids!
Jewel & blu - 我们的孩子
- oh right! I leave them with Tiny. -Tiny?
-哦 对了 我交给小不点了 -小不点！
Why? She is the excellent babysitter.
啥了? 她可是这里最棒的保姆
I'm a horrible babysitter.
我是这里最差劲的保姆
This's gonna be awesome!
这一定会很炫的
All right,I've done all the calculations
行了 我已经计算过了
And each explosion will be perfectly synced to the beat.
每次爆炸都会完美的踩在节奏点上
Unless I didn't carry the one...
除非我没有算上这个...
Here's my vision...Red, blue, green, yellow, yellow... purple.
我觉得...这里会有红色 蓝色 绿色 黄色...紫色
And it'my vision...
我觉得会是...
I don't think your parents will like see that very much
我觉得你们爸妈不会想看到这个的
Here we go.
那我们开始吧
- Where are you going, little birds? - What is it?
-你这是要去哪儿啊小鸟    -这是什么？
- Ah Dad! - Guys, You know the rules
-爸爸   -你们知道规矩的
No pyrotechnics without adult supervision.
没有大人的监督 不能放烟花
We ask Tiny
我们问过小不点了
That's even worse. Sorry Tiny.
这就更糟了 抱歉小不点
You don't have to need pay me, Senior.Blu.
工钱我不要了 布鲁先生
Kids next time, ask me.
下次玩 一定要先问我
- But you always says no.  - No I don't.
-可你每次都说不  -不 我没有
- Daddy, you're in denial.
-爸爸 你在否认现实
Ok honey, did I always say no?
-好吧 亲爱的 我经常说不嚒
Yes! oh I mean...no...
是的 哦 我是说...不...
Great, now Mom same too.
太好了，现在妈妈也在说不了
Listen, we are the last blue speakes Macaws left on this planet
听着 我们是地球上最后的蓝斯皮克斯金刚鹦鹉
We have to stay safe.
我们得注意安全
- Birds with blue feathers...
-有蓝色羽毛的鸟
-Have to stick together
-要团结在一起
I smell chicken.
我闻到烤鸡味了
No, no, no!
啊 不不不....
By my count he said "no" 27 times today.
根据我的计算 这是他今天说的第27个不了
- Help! - What?
-救命   -啊...
Everybody fly!
大家伙 快跑
Oh man! How can Dad gets time all the fun?
这不公平 凭什么 只有爸爸玩的这么爽
Look! It worked!
看啊 成功了
Well, this year has a great started.
看来今年开了个好头
RIO 2
里约大冒险 2
Amazon Expedition. 7th day.
亚马逊之行 第七天
3200km from Rio
距里约热内卢 2000英里
We can reach the center of the rainforest.
我们到达热带雨林的中心
We are surrounded by plants and animals struggling for survival.
当我们沿着河流毫不费力的向前划行的时候
As we effortlessly guide down the river.
周围都是挣扎生存的植物和动物
Effortless for you.
毫不费力的是你
Wow! How pretty!
哇哦 好漂亮
Spit it out! Spit it out!
吐出来 快吐出来
We are nearly the nature ground of the Amazon uru-buck.
我们已经接近亚马逊树林鹌鹑的栖息地
6 months ago, we rescued this little bird form smugglers.
六个月前我们从走私者手中救下这只小鸟
It was sick, malnourished, with a broken leg.
那时候它生着病，营养不良 还断了一条腿
But now, my trusty assistant...
而现在 我可靠的助手..
I mean, loveing wife and colleague
我是说我的妻子兼同事
will release it back to natural habitat.
就要把它放归回自然
It's okay, you can go now. Just like this.
都没事了 你可以走的 就像这样
Let me talk to her.
还是让我跟他说吧
Go on!
走吧
- Do you think she's gonna be okay? - Give her some time
-你觉得他会没事吗   -给他一点时间
Welcome home.
欢迎回家
Wait a minute. What she is saying, Tulio?
等一下 它..好像在说什么 图里奥
It is just hard for her to say goodbye.
他是不舍得我们 在和我们说再见
No, I think is trying to warn us.
不 我觉得他好像在警告我们
No,no,no, Linda,It may be some mating dance.
不不不 琳达 这可能是吸引异性的舞蹈
Tulio, look! Paddle! now!
图里奥 看那 快划 快啊
Okay, okay!
好的 好的
To the right ! No,no the left
往右...不不不 往左
Forward! Forward!
往前 往前
Make up your mind, Tulio!
你想清楚再说 图里奥
Chese and sprinkles!
这下可糟了
Oh no! Row, row! Faster!
哦 不  快划快划 快点！
Linda!
琳达
Tulio
图里奥
Thank heavens you're ok.
感谢上帝 你没有事
Tulio, is that...
图里奥 这是..
Linda, this is incredible!
啊 琳达 真难以置信
《RIO RIO》
Goodmornning, Jewel
早上好 珠儿
Hey,everyone look what I found.
嘿 你们看我找到了什么
Blu ?
布鲁？
Kids?
孩子们？
Where's everyone...
大家都去哪儿了？
Okay, who is ready to some Breakfast?  -Unbelievable.
-好了 谁肚子饿了想吃早饭   -难以置信
Did you know that this whole pancakes
你知道么 那些全麦煎饼
has twice the vitamins and minerals?
所含的维生素矿物质是普通煎饼的两倍
and with blueberries is 4 times to tasty.
而且加上蓝莓后味道会好上4倍
Hey Where are the blueberries?
嘿 蓝莓都哪去了
Oh Dad, looking for this?
爸爸 你在找这个吗
bring it!
给我吧
In the final minutes, he has his magic in feet
已经到了最后关头 他的脚仿佛有魔力一样
he shoots!
他射门了
- Goal!
球进了！
Oh yeh, I got, I'm good.
噢耶 我接到了 我真是太棒了
Hands up, Dad.
爸爸 注意了
Aho!
啊哦
Awesome!
哦 帅呆了
Hi, Mom!
嗨  妈妈
- Busted. - Time to go.
-这下惨了  -该走了
Hi, honey. Are you hungry?
亲爱的 你饿了吗
Blu, we talked about this.
布鲁 我跟你说过的
Did we?Ummm,so,uhhh,so whatta you got there?
是吗 我不记得了 哦 对的 你拿的是什么
- Breakfast. - That's funny, but Seriously what is that?
-早饭  -很好笑 不过  说真的 这是什么
It's a Brazil nut.
这是个巴西栗
I never thought I'd find one this close to the city.
离城市这么近的地方居然也有
- I want to show the kids how to open it. - I mean, so?
-我要教孩子们怎么打开  -你是说打开这个吗
Daddy already shown us.
爸爸已经教过我们了
Wait  back.
等等 来了
Mom  Dad  you're on TV.
爸爸妈妈 你们上电视了
Doctor Tulio Monteiro,the"birdman"of Brazial
巴西鸟类学家图里奥蒙泰罗博士
announced a major discovery today
今天宣布了一项重大发现
We believe we having encountered a wild blue speakes macaw
我们相信 我们在亚马逊丛林深处找到了野生的
in Amazon jungle
蓝色金刚鹦鹉
The blue speakes Macaw was thought practically extinct
蓝色金刚鹦鹉之前被认为在野外全部灭绝了
With the last remain family
仅存的一家鹦鹉
living under the protection at the "blu" bird's shrine In Rio de Janeiro
目前居住在里约的布鲁鸟类保护区
We are famous .
我们出名了
If these birds can be found  their home will be saved
如果找到这些野生鹦鹉 他们的家园将受到保护
There may be the whole flock of birds there
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
If here is, we'll find them and protect them
如果真的有 我们会找到他们 并保护他们
Hi, Blu!
你好 布鲁
Hi, Linda!
你好 琳达
We are not the only ones.
我们不是唯一的
There are more of us there.
我们还有活着的同类啊
- Yes, that's great.  - All this time I thought...
-是啊 太好了 -这么长时间 我一直...
I thought we were alone.
我一直以为...我们是孤独的
This was not bad?
嘿 以前也没有那么糟糕
Of course not, but...
是挺好的 可是...
Imagine there was a whole flock of us.
想象一下 有一大群同类
How amazing will that being!
那该有多么美妙啊
- We have to do something.  - We do?
-我们得做点什么   -真的吗
Yes, we have to fly to Amazon
对 我们去亚马逊
And help Linda and Tulio find them.
去帮助琳达和图里奥找到他们
Wow...We can't just pack up and go.
哦...我们不能说走就走
Why not? It's time this family feel the wind in their wings.
为什么不能 现在正是时候出去让翅膀吹吹风了
Look at us! IPod television pancakes?
看看我们 音乐播放器 电视 煎饼
We are not people, we are birds!
亲爱的 我们不是人类 我们可是鸟
We have get out to the wild and be birds, Blu.
我们应该回到野外 做真正的鸟 布鲁
Let the kids know their roots
让孩子们回到大自然吧
Show them what I had.
看看我们从前的生活
They need this we need this.
他们需要这样 我们也需要
Come on Blu! What do you say?
来吧，布鲁！你说呢？
I do not know. Maybe, but...
我不知道...也许吧...
He didn't say no.
他没有说不
That's mean he probabiliy said yes.
这就意味着他说 行
- What, no!  - It will be so much fun!
-嘿 等一下   -亲爱的，一定会很好玩！
We are come to the Amazon.
耶...我们要去亚马逊咯
Wait, what is the Amazon?
等一下，亚马逊是什么？
The Amazon is one of the most danger ecosystems
亚马逊，目前世界上最濒危的生态系统之一
Due to illegal deforestation and framing
由于非法砍伐和耕种
Let's hope the dr.Monteiro and his team
我们希望博士和他的团队
find these rare birds so their home can be save
能找到那些珍惜鸟类，让他们的家园得以保存
There may be the whole flockout of there
那里可能有很多这种鹦鹉
If there is, we'll find them and protect them
如果真的有，我们会找到它们并保护他们
Ecochatos. get my boat ready.
Ecochatos 把我的船准备好
I need to do this  personally.
我要亲自去处理这件事情
Next
下一个
It's time for me, everybody can go home now.
轮到我了，行了你们可以回家了
You are looking for the next King of Carnival.
你们正在看着的下一位，狂欢之王
Hi,big bird, good luck!
嘿 大鸟 祝你好运
Whach out buddy!
走路小心点，别躺着进去！
Bravo!
棒极了！
Bravo! That was amazing!
棒极了！你唱的真是太好了
Eva, darling, you hit every note.
我亲爱的，你刚才一个音符也没落下
-Huh guys?  -Yeah yeah
-伙计们？  -对！是的！
In various a lot of notes I've ever heard of.
还多了很多我从来没听过的音
- Rafa! - Do not worry!
-拉斐尔  -别 别担心
I'll talk to them.
我会和他们说的
We will find a perfect part for you!
我会为你找到完美的角色！
Antarctica maybe.
嗯...潜规则也没用
You bet! Bye bye!
最好如此 回头见
Goodbye, boys!
再见 孩子们！
See you back at home, my tasty mango!
我们家里见，我的美味小芒果
None of the acts are inspiring.I am just not inspired!
哎...这些表演一点都不好 我连一点灵感都没有
The carnival is right on the corner.
狂欢节眼看就要到了
And our reputations are on the line.
我们的名声会毁于一旦的
Copy yeat! we need something make us wild
明白！我们需要一些能让我们嗨起来的节奏
Something like jungle. We need something pop...
我们需要 动感 火爆 激情
You know  pop is that word?
你知道激情怎么说么？
- Pop  - Next.
啪...下一个...
- Blu!  - Sorry, man!
-布鲁  -对不起兄弟
It's Okay, Luiz! Good to see you too!
没关系 路易兹 我也很高兴见到你
Listen, Blu, we are looking for a singer
听着 布鲁 我们在寻找一位歌手
a dancer, the whole package.
一个舞者 样样都会的
Yeah and you're more of a mumbler-shuffer.you catch my drift?
不要唱歌跑调 跳舞摔跤的 你懂我的意思么？
No I'm not here for the audition.
我不是来面试的
I got news!
我有事情要宣布
I'm going to the Amazon.
我准备要去亚马逊了
Amazon!
亚马逊
That's wild.
那可真够野的
Yes, Jewel think will be good for us.
是呀 珠儿觉得这对我们有好处
- How wild?  - Real wild.
-有多野  -超级宇宙无敌野
There mosquitoes suck your blood like slurpess.
那里的蚊子能够一口吸干你的
There snakes that swallow you whole.
那里的蛇能一口将你整个吞下去
There carnivorous piranhas... eat fresh
那里还有吃肉的食人鱼 会吃肉的！
Great,sounds pretty nice!
哦！好极了 真不赖
- I will not going! -Gus guys guys!
-我不去了   -得了伙计们
Blu, you have nothing to worry about.
布鲁 你根本不用担心这些
All those stories are highly exaggerated.
他们说的这些都有点夸张的过分了
- You think so?  - Of course!
-你真的这么想？  -当然了！
If it is important to Jewel, Just do it.
如果这对珠儿很重要 那你就去吧
Happy wife happy life...
老婆开心 日子舒心...
- Remember that.  - Okay, you're right.
-一定要记住   -好的 对!
You know,a little family vacation, might actually be fun.
你说的对 就当全家一起去度假 一定很有趣
Plus it's not like it's foever!
再说了 又不是定居在那里
That's the spirit.
这就对了
Okay, thanks guys!
好的 谢谢伙计们！
See you in a couple of weeks.
过段时间见
- Safe treavles Blu!  - Bring me back a souvenir!
-一路顺风 布鲁   -记得带纪念品回来
Dog, he can't come back.
得了 他不会回来了
He's end...there.
他一定会挂在那里的
Amazon!
亚马逊！
Let's go! Come on  Dad! come on!
我们走 快点爸爸 快点
Ok, bug spray check, water purifier cheak, Band-aids...
好的 驱虫剂 净水剂 还有创可贴
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
哦 我好像忘了点什么
Wow! Cool, the all-in-one Adventurer's knife.
哇哦 酷 是多功能瑞士军刀
-I'll be in charge of this. -That's not for you!
-这个交给我来弄吧 -这不是给你准备的
Dad, look at this!
嘿 爸爸 来看我这个
Did you know the Amazon has snakes that can swallow you whole?
你知道亚马逊的蛇能一口把你吃掉吗？
Actually, Bia ,all those stories are highly exaggerated
事实上这些故事写得太夸张了
No, really! Look!
不一定吧 你看这个
Oh..That's sick!
哦 这个好恶心啊
All right, Are we ready to go?
准备好出发了吗？
A fanny pack?
你带了个腰包？
Yeah Linda gave it to me, I need it for the GPS.
是的 琳达给我的 用来装GPS定位
Where's the GPS.
哦 我的GPS呢
Carla  we're leaveing.
卡拉 我们要走啦
I'm not going! It's gonna be lame.
我才不去呢！肯定很无聊
OK, Here it is!
行了 找到了
The voice recognition makes totally easier. Here watch this..
它有语音识别功能 很好用的 你看着
Finding Linda and Tulio.
给我找琳达和图里奥
Seaching for dining in Tokyo
正在搜索 去东京吃料理
Ok,actually that is a nice suggestion.
好的 额 事实上这个还真不错
- You trust this woman?  - Yes, I do.
-你相信这个女人？  -是的 我相信
Wait us family, I will going too.
嘿 等下伙计们 我们也要一起去
Do not worry buddy. We'll get you back.
别担心哥们 我们会罩着你的
- Eva let you come?  - Sure!
-你老婆让你去了吗？  -当然！
Promised her a place in the carnival show.
我答应她在狂欢演出里给他弄个角色
- You did what?  -You guys are late.
-答应他什么   -你们迟到了
-Clock late. - But musicians early.
-是有点晚  -但我们可是音乐家
Wait your guys are coming?
等等 你们也要去吗？
We wouldn't miss it for the world.
我们当然不会错过
We're gonna scout the wildest coolest talent in that jungle.
我们要去丛林寻找最棒的歌手
And it's our inspiration for the carnival show.
这是我们今年狂欢节演出的创作灵感
Amazon untamed.
狂野的 亚马逊
Cool! I mean... Okay...
酷 我是说...好吧
I guess I will go.
我也会去的
Amazon jungle for bust, baby!
去亚马逊放手一搏
Who's ready for a tropical adventure?
都准备好去热带探险了么
Guys, wait up! We didn't do a head count! Hey guys wait up!
等等 等等 孩子们 还没有点名
Recalculating
重新规划路线
Hey Birds come back!
嘿 小鸟 快回来
They were go without me..again!
又是这样 丢下我自己走了！
This is Sadly!
太让人伤心了！
《O Vida》
里约热内卢
欧鲁普雷图
巴西利亚
Heavy traffic ahead
前方道路 拥堵
Great..Thanks a lot GPS lady.
多谢了 GPS小姐
Faster, faster!
快点 快点 快点
Slower...
慢点...
Here we are, kids! The gate way to the Amazon.
我们到了孩子们，这里就是亚马逊的大门了
"alive .." Or... Do not be!
生存 还是....毁灭
That is the question!
这是个问题
Whether is nobler in the mind to suffer the slings
究竟哪一个更高贵 去忍受这命运
And arrows of outrageous fortune
还是去忍受着无边的烦恼
Or to take arms against a sea of troubles
经受无边的摧残
And by opposing end them
还是把它忘个干净
Oh that's beautiful Nigel. What does it mean?
噢 真实太美妙了 奈杰尔 这是什么意思
Death Gabi.
死亡 噶比
Is about death.
说的是死亡
Oh Nigel, I love it when you get all dark and brooding.
哦 奈杰尔 我爱死你了
Hey bird, it's showtime!
嘿 笨鸟 该上场了
My audience waits!
我的观众正等着我呢
From the streets of Rio to the Amazon jungle
从里约的丛林 到亚马逊的街头
The Bird of mystery.
有请 神秘的大鸟
Don't be shine learn your destiny
别害羞，快来了解属于你的命运吧
Hey Get away form the ants. Back to work.
喂 别打蚂蚁的主意 干你的活去
Mami, I want one, I want to furtune!
妈妈 我要玩这个 占卜
Welcome, madam.
欢迎光临 夫人
This amazing Cockatoo reveal your future.
这只难以置信的鹦鹉 能够预示你的未来
All right bird.Take the furture.
好了小鸟 选一个吧
Come on bird!
快点 小鸟
You're doing right, Nigel.
你干的很好 奈杰尔
Pick it up already.
快一点
Come on,almost there.No more flying today
加油 伙计们 就快到了 今天不用再飞了
We've got a boat to catch.
晚一点 我们能赶上一艘船
According my friend here will get there by the morning.
根据GPS的计算 明天一早我们就能到
You will live but could never fly again
他能活下来 但永远也飞不起来了
Come on!  My luck
快点 小鸟 快给我算命
- You are very cute.- Why is it taking so long
-很好奈杰尔  -怎么要这么长时间
That blue bird caused my misery
我会这么惨 都是那只蓝色的鸟害的
Nice birddy.
小鸟乖
Why are you hitting yourself? Why are you hitting yourself?
为什么要打自己 为什么要打自己
Wow..Nigel is very macho.
哇哦 奈杰尔好有男子汉气概
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm free!
我自由了
Poisonous frog!
这里有只箭毒蛙
The croaking cockatoo doth bellow  for revenge.
嘎嘎叫的凤头鹦鹉 呐喊着要去复仇
That's Shakespeare, by the way.
这是莎士比亚写得
Without your interpretation it's nothing. -Good point.
-没有你的表演 他一文不值  -说得好
一个完成旧任务的好时机
Oh this air is so freshion.
哦 这空气 又清新 又舒适
Goodbye, smelly city air!
再见了 城市里的雾霾
Yes, goodbye.
对！再见！
Hey Thanks for doing this. I really appreciate.
嘿 谢谢你能为我这样做 真的很谢谢你
I would do anything for you.
为了你 我愿意做任何事情
- You know that, right? - Of course I know.
-你懂得 对么？  -我当然懂
We aren't here for neck, We are here to revenge.
我们不是来这吃点心的 我们是来复仇的
When these pesky passengers flat sleep
等乘客都睡着的时候
We'll show our blue friends some love
我们就好好关爱下我的蓝色朋友们
Some poisonously love.
给他们一点...毒爱
Oh..That is my specialty.
哦 这个我最拿手了
We will attack at midnight hour because it is more evil.
我们在午夜发动攻击 这样显得更加邪恶
Stay alert.
保持警惕
Midnight. Time to attack!
午夜！袭击的时间
Nigel. Nigel.
奈杰尔 奈杰尔
Look for us mistys.
看看我们两个另类的生物
A toxic frog and a flyless freak.
一只剧毒的青蛙 一只不会飞的怪鸟
So different and yet the same
我们如此的不同 又如此的相同
My darling whilesleep all is well We're friends and that's swell
亲爱的 当你睡着了 我们是朋友 那样很好
But the truth I have a secret to tell...I love you
可是有个秘密一定要告诉你....我爱你
People says it is wrong and absurda frog and a bird love
人们说这不对 很可笑 一只青蛙怎么和鸟恋爱
《Poisonous Love》
But I know in my heart this is ment to be
可我心里知道 这是命中注定的
If only we could could hug and could kiss be in heavenly bliss
如果我们能拥抱亲吻 那真是天堂般的幸福
But your lungs would explode and you'd look just like this
可你的肺会烂掉 就像这样
As you'd hemorrhage and gag would cough up your face turn blue
你会窒息 脸涨成蓝色
Oh
哦...
But darling I'll protect you
不过亲爱的 我会照顾你
Do not worry just chill
我会的 你尽管放松
Cause there isn't a bird that I wouldn't kill ..for you
因为我能杀掉任何鸟 只要是为了你
Can't you see...
你看不出来吗
oh we were destined to be
我们注定要在一起
For we have love
因为我们的爱
Poisonous love
有毒的爱...
-Love - Yes i know
-爱...  -虽然 是的
- Yes
是的
I know that you can't hold me
我知道你没法拥抱我
Feel me close now
投入我的怀抱吧
Your loving wings enfold me
你爱的翅膀 围绕着我
Fate told me..love..
命运告诉我 爱...
Poisonous love...
有毒的爱...
Standing here
站在这里
You're so near and..
你离我是如此的近 可是..
Yet so far..like a star
-又那么远  -就像一颗星星
Here we are
我们到了
- Where - What to do
-哪儿？  -该怎么办？
oh poo
哦
Your my romeo I'm juliet
你是我的罗密欧 我是你的朱丽叶
We are so perfect and yet if we touch not by much
我们天生一对 可是 如果我们触碰哪怕一点点
Still on all you can bet
可以确信一点
It's good bye
那就是 永别
And I'll cry
我会哭泣
As you die
因为你已不再
From our poisonous...
死于我们有毒的...
Love...
爱...
What a nightmare.
好可怕的梦
Charli, you were supposed to wake me.
查理 你应该把我叫醒的
It's time.
要行动了
I love being on team of Nigel.
能做奈杰尔的搭档真好
I can not think of anything more romantic than
我想不出什么比在夜晚下
poisoning passengers on a moonlight cruise
给乘客下毒更浪漫的事情了
Stop!
住手
That one is mine.
那家伙是我的
Twinkle, twinkle, little Bluey.How I wondered where were you?
一闪一闪小布鲁...找你找得好辛苦...
Up above the world so high.
高高的挂在天空中...
Are you ready to die?
今天让你..一命呜呼
You need one breath mint.
你应该吃块绿箭薄荷糖
Even you sleep you mock me?
你睡着了都要嘲笑我！
Wait for me.
等等我
Do not leave me!
别丢下我
- Tiago, stop leaveing around. - I didn't do anything.
-迪耶戈 别到处乱跑  -我什么也没干啊
Tiago Gunderson, listen to your mother.
孩子 听你妈妈的话
Oh man.
哦 天
-We're almost there right. -Hey Guys wait up...
-我们快到了  -等一下伙计们
Remember... Birds have...never mind.
记住 有蓝色....算了
They are getting away.
他们都跑了
Wake up, you ant-eating idiot. follow them!
快醒醒 你这个吃蚂蚁的笨蛋 快跟上他们
Better! Now get to times faster!
好多了 现在给我快一点
River hugs!
这个笨蛋！
You! I always suspected that was dumber than a monkey.
我一直在想 你是不是比猴子还笨
And now I know.
现在我懂了
Boss, what are you doing in the jungle?
老板 您来丛林里干什么？
Perhaps the better question is: What are they doing?
你应该问他们来这里干什么
Nature Freaks.
那些环保狂
Too million hectares of jungle
这里有几百万平方英里的丛林
And they play in my backyard?
可替他们偏偏跑到这里来
I don't think so.
我可不是好惹的家伙
As you know my friends, these our operations
你也知道 朋友 我们的伐木作业
is a bit... illegal.
稍微有点....违法
If these two nuts found those birds, we have no business
如果这些人找到那些鸟 我们的生意就完了
And that's why you must end their little bird watching expedition
所以你现在要尽快结束他们的寻鸟丛林探险
Find them! And get rid of them.
找到他们 赶走他们
The rest of you go cut some trees.
其余的人 都给我砍树去
Who cares a bunch of birds?
谁在乎一群什么破鸟
The macaws should be nesting near the Brazial nut trees
鹦鹉会把鸟巢筑在巴西栗树附近
So..I think that we should continue with...
所以我觉得我们应该...
Tulio, are you listening to me?
图里奥 你在听我说话吗
You have arrived at your destination
你已到达目的地
You see? It worked like a charm. Here we are.
看！是不是很管用 我们到了
Where?
这是哪？
Oh..These things have a margin of error.
嗯 这东西稍微有点误差
I told you not trust that woman.
我跟你说过别相信那个女人
That's a Heliconius larva.it's about to enter the pupa state
这是一个幼虫 他就要进入变蛹的阶段了
Ha! You said poop
哈 你说桶
-hey kids stay close. -I'll get them.
-你们跟紧了  -我要去找他们
Okay, you stay here and I take a look around.
好吧 你们留在这里别动 我去周边看看
Do not worry, we'll be here.Not going anywhere.
别担心 我们就在这 我们哪儿都不去
--My feathers is poppin'up on the back ofmy neck.
-我后背的羽毛都竖起来了
- I don't like this.
-我可不喜欢这个感觉
Let's back it up.
我们掉头吧
Bia? Tiago!
比亚 迪耶戈
Come on lady don't let me down.
拜托 小姐 别让我失望
Calculating route to: funky town
规划前往...秀场的路线
Ok great
好吧 太好了
Ok guys...Guys?
伙计们？
Haha come on guys. Very funny.
呵呵 可以 这很好玩
Funny same. Very clever.
很好 很好 很聪明的玩笑
Jewel where are you?
珠儿 你在哪？
Kids? Jewel?
孩子们 老婆？
Ah it's a Macaw! Linda!
啊 蓝色金刚鹦鹉 琳达！
Let me go!
放开我
Let me go! you barbarian.
放开我 你这个野蛮人
Blu?
布鲁？
I swear that's sound like my Blu.
我发誓 这声音听起来像布鲁的
That's impossible, Linda.
不 不可能 琳达
He is home in Rio safe and sound.
他在家里 既舒适又安全
I am an americian citizen, you savage!
我可是美国公民 你这个野蛮人
I demand to see my ambassador.I know my rights.
我要求见美国大使 我知道我有这个权利
I know my rights.
我有这个权利
Back up barbarian.
退后 野蛮人
Yeah That's right.Is a spoon and a fork.
对 没错 这是个勺子 也是个叉子
Be afraid. Be very afraid.
害怕了吧 怕的发抖了吧
Aho my buddy put that spork down.
啊哦...把你的东西放下
Let me go...leave me. Luckily I'm bigger.
放开我...有种来啊
I can't believe we found them.
真不敢相信 我们找到他们了
Well, technically they found us.
严格的说 是他们找到了我们
Ok we're going to need some name tags.
好吧 得找点东西来写名字
Oh hello em.. There are mints.
哦 那是绿箭薄荷糖
Don't you need it but they are good.you eat them.
你用不到它 不过味道还不错...你可以试试
No no no... not the whole box.
不 别连盒都吞下去
Get that out of your mouth
赶快..把它..吐出来
还记得第一部里珠儿还有布鲁么？
What is this doing here? What's going on?
出什么事情 怎么了？
We found them flying too close to the humans.
我们发现他们飞得离人类太近
What? And who are you?
什么 你是谁？
Er...This is not the appropriate answer.I asked a question.
额 可不是一个合适的回答 我问你话呢
Where did you come from?
你们到底从哪来
-Hey back off
- 嘿 退后
-Excuse me young lady, is it...
- 不好意思小姐...
I can't believe it.
真不敢相信
How... How did this...
这...这怎么可能
Some loggers came
伐木工来的时候到处都是大火
There was fire and.. so much smoke.
到处都是浓烟 然后...
I hide you under my wing.
我把你藏在翅膀下面
-And you were.. -Gone
然后你就...不见了
I was looking everywhere for you.
我一直在找你
I'm here
我在这
Daddy
爸爸
Daddy?
爸爸？
I missed you.
我好想你
It's Okay.It's Okay. Now...
没事了 一切都过去了
Dad has you.
有爸爸在
Look at you. It's my little girl.
看看你 我的小女儿
Have grown up.
已经长大了
So beautiful.
长得这么漂亮
Just like your mother.
就像你的妈妈一样
I'm so sorry I missed you.
对不起 我把你弄丢了
I can not imagine you were alone all this time.
我无法想象这些年你一个人到底怎么过来的
It's okay, Dad. I wasn't alone.
没什么 爸爸 我不孤单
Blu found me.
布鲁找到我了
Nice to meet you Sir.
很高兴见到你 先生
Cut down wings away Blu.Now come here.
把翅膀收起来 布鲁 到我这来
- Sure okay. - Closer.
-当然   -近一点
- Really? - Closer.
-是吗？ -再近点
You brought my jewell back to me.
你把我女儿带回来了
I thank you.
我谢谢你
I'll hug you now.
现在我要拥抱你
Em..Okay.
额 好的
- Come here. - Here we are.
-行了 过来吧   -抱上了
My pleasure.
真是我的荣幸
Nico, Are you crying?
什么 你在哭吗？
It's a heavy moment and I'm very vulnerable right now.
看到这么感人的场面 我内心很脆弱啊
Let me give you an arm.
拥抱吧 我们
Mom, are you okay?
妈妈 你没事吧
Mom ? I'm Grandpa.
妈妈？我当外公了
I'm Grandpa.
我当外公了
Look at me I'm a Grandpa!
看看 我是外公了
Daddy is this: Carla Bia and Tiago.
爸爸 这是卡拉 比亚 迪耶戈
- Nice to meet you, sir
-你好呀 先生
- There is no sir around here, my young lady.
-不要叫我先生 我的小姐
-You'll call me papa
-你应该叫我..帕帕
- Pa Pa? Oh I like that.
-帕帕 哦 我喜欢
I'm the papa papa. I'm papa papa.
我是外公啦 太好啦  我是外公啦
Kids, go easy on old grandpa
别把外公弄伤了 孩子们
You call me sir.
你还叫我先生
My daughter has returned.
我女儿回来啦
For years we live because humans fleeing push us
这些年我们东躲西藏 人类把我们逼往
deep into the jungle.
越来越深的丛林
不过你看 我们找到了一个避难所 But as you can see we‘re found a sanctuary.
A place we can finally put down roots.
我们终于可以在这里扎根了
Everyone. Come on. All leave the nest.
大伙们 出来吧
My daughter is home.
我女儿回来啦
Come birds. My Jewel is back.
出来吧小鸟们  我的珠儿回来啦
Jewel?
珠儿？
Make way, make way. Jewel!
让开  让开 珠儿！
Aunt Mimi? Aunt Mimi!
咪咪婶婶 咪咪婶婶
I felt you so much.
哦 我想死你了
My wild little flower has return.
我的小野花终于回家了
I knew you are coming back.
我就知道你会回来
I saw the specks of dropings.
我会用鸟粪算命
Look at these puppies.
看看这些小家伙们
Who's the most cutest little macaws?
谁是可爱的小蓝皮克斯鹦鹉
Oh you look big for your age.
哦 你长得可有点着急啊
Mimi  this is the Bilu.
哦 咪咪婶 这是苏
Actually I am the Blu.
事实上我叫布鲁
- We are all - It's mean is my name.
-我们都是鹦鹉 呵呵   -我名字是Blu
So that is why we call blue macaws.
金刚鹦鹉都是蓝色的
Just go with it.
你就依着她吧
《Welcome Back》
So that's what a blue macaw is supposed to look like?
原来你在这种鸟里长得算是挫的
Look it shining
看她多耀眼
Her feathers is glow
她的羽毛闪闪发光
Now the jungle is smiling
现在丛林都在欢笑
Because our baby is home.
因为我们的宝贝回来了
Can you feel what I feeled
你是否和我一样的感受
That day has come last
因为这一天终于来到
Our precious Jade has returned
我们心爱的珠珠回来了
I'll be the first to say welcome back
我要第一个唱出来 欢迎回来
Roberto, I...
罗伯特....我
Welcome back
欢迎回来
I say welcome back welcome welcome...
我是说 欢迎 欢迎 欢迎 欢迎
Back...
回来...
- Wow..You look great. - So do you.
-哇 你看上去棒极了   -你也是
Hey, hi, hello. I am the Jewel significant other.
嗨 你好 我是珠儿的...重要的那一位
So you're the lucky bird who swept Ju-Ju of her feet, huh?
哦 那你就是那个俘获了珠珠芳心的幸运鸟
- Ju-Ju? - Yeah.
-珠珠？  -是啊
When we were kids we called cute name in each other.
我们小时候一直给对方起可爱的小名
We did, I called him Beto.
是的 我叫他背头...呵呵
That's adorable. I love doing nicknames.
那真可爱 我也喜欢起小名
You never mentioned any Roberto.
你可从来没提起过什么罗伯特
There was nothing to mention.
那是他没有什么可提的啊
Hey..There is my wing man.
嘿..我的搭档来了
We can rest with Rober to look out.
有罗伯特放哨 我们都能安心睡觉了
Eduardo taught me everything I know.
多亏艾迪教会我一切
- He is the bird.
-全靠你这只好鸟
-No.. You're the bird!
-不 你才是好鸟...
-No, you're the bird.  -You're the bird
-不 你是只好鸟   -你才是好鸟...
We get it. You both are birds.
知道了 你们两个都是好鸟
Now can we stop yapping and start party
能不能别唧唧歪歪了 开始聚会吧
《Beautiful Creatures》
Oh well..I remember this song.
哇哦...我记得这首歌
How could you forget? It's in our blood baby.
怎么可能忘记 它一直流淌在我们的血液里
It's who we are.
这是只属于我们的歌
You don't mind if I borrow her for a minute, do you
不介意我借用她一会吧？嗯...
- Have you commented...- Come on, Ju-Ju let's go.
-额 事实上我...   -来吧 珠珠 开始了
Let's come together  singing love and harmoni
We are so different  but the same inside our hearts
Beautiful colors  as far as the eyes can see ya
Open your wings  fly when you hear the call
Let's celebrate  calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures
Come this way celebrate
Laugh and dance all the way
Follow me sing along
-这个地方真是潜力无穷啊  -我好喜欢他们这种歌
Lah lah bah bah boom boom...
Ja disse que Jade chegou
Ja disse que ja disse que Jade chegou...
Pop-pop  I am the pop-pop
I am the tchh I am your pop-pop
I am the pop-pop-pop  tchch pop-pop-pop
I am the pop-pop the tchhhchhc
Let's celebrate  calling the beautiful creatures
Come spread your wings  dance and sing songs about freedom
Like lah lah lah hoo hoo
One for the jungle familia
Like bah bah bah boo boo
Calling the beautiful creatures...
You are the one who knows what being alone and...
只有你能理解 孤苦伶仃是什么感觉
Misunderstood. you are the "evil" to my "mortal".
额 你邪恶 我狠毒 哦呵呵
I can see why they call you Gabi
你应该改个名字叫话唠
Where are you,you filthy fowl
在哪儿呢 你这个肮脏的家禽
Hold!
站住
I've been going about this all wrong
我之前的行动战略不对
I need to search him from higher around.
我应该去更高的地方找
You stay there for almost full second this time.
哦 你刚才腾空了将近整整一秒钟
Bravo! Bravissimo!
太棒了 简直太NB了
What you do looking at? Take me up there.
你看什么看 帮我上去
Higher.
高点
Even higher.
再高点
A little bit higher.
稍微再高点
lower lower now.Yes... perfect.
低点 现在低点 很好 现在正好
Ugh, it's an infestation
哇哦 这么一大群祸害
Keep celebrate, I'll be pooping on your party pronptly.
呵呵 继续庆祝吧 你们很快就要高兴不起来了
Hi, Nico. Hi, Peter.
嗨 尼克  嗨 佩克罗
We have come to the right place. This is zhe pop in Amazon.
我们来对地方了 这就是火爆 亚马逊的火爆
We could bring these macaws back to Rio
我们要把这些金刚鹦鹉带回里约
And have the best carnaval show ever. I'm inspired.
参加有史以来最棒的狂欢节演出 我现在灵感如泉涌
Sorry to break it your cityboys
抱歉 城里来的鸟
But you'll have to find some other talent
我看你们还是去找别的明星吧
nobody leaves the tribe.
谁也不许离开这里
And no human things in jungle.
哦 还有 丛林里不许留下人类的东西
Understand?
听懂了么
What's his problem?
什么 他什么毛病
I feel naked...
我被扒光了...
We could been legends
差点就能流芳百世了
We are already awesome, but you know what I'm saying
我们已经超级无敌了 可是...你懂我的意思吗
We had all.
什么都有啊
The undiscovered talent,the big idea and the inspiration
没被发掘的明星 好的创意
but if we can not take this guys to Rio ..
可是没有办法把他们带回里约...
We got nothing.
就什么都没有
Nothing?
什么都没有？
Hold your mangoes, we still have Eva
别那么失落嘛 不是还有我老婆吗
What?
怎么
Wow You still got zhe move, Ju-Ju
哇哦 你跳的还是那么好 珠珠
- I'm so exhausted.
-我快累死了
-Yeah, we should get some rest
-是啊 我们该去休息了
Find a local innl or B&B nearby.
找个旅馆或者酒店
What is this crazy talk?
你在胡说些什么啊
Now, you guys are staying in my nest
不 你们就住我家里
I'm on charge tonight.
今晚我巡逻
- My house is all yours.
-我的家 就是你们的家
- That's really nice, Beto.
-你真是太好了 背头
Thank you but we're fine
谢谢 但我觉得我们能搞定
Besides our whole family couldn't possibly fit in your bachelor pad
再说我们一大家子 住单身公寓 挤不下
Wow!
哇哦
Real estate must be pretty cheap around here.
这里的房价一定非常低吧
Wow...This is incredible.
哇哦 真是不可思议
Oh, this old nest?
你说这里?
It's just something I put together last minute
这只是我最近随便弄的
With my own two wings, of course.
当然 用的是我的两只翅膀
And my strength.
我的力气
And my breast.
还有我的肌肉（...）
Daddy is huge It has 6 bedrooms.
爸爸 这里好大 有六个卧室呢
- I'll get zhe big one.
-我要最大的这间
- No, I'm the oldest.
-我是最大的
Only for 3 minutes and 2.5 seconds.
就比我大3分钟外加2.5秒
I hoped to one day be blessed
我真希望有一天
with a bunch of little Betinhos cause my own.
我也有一群小鬼抢房间
- I think you did
-一定会的
- No way! A bird bath!
-不会吧 这里还有鸟浴盆
- And it's Jacuzzi!
还有按摩
Blu meet you something
嘿 布鲁 我告诉你
If anything..I mean anything ever happen to you
如果你出了任何事 任何...
I'll take care of your family.
我会帮忙照顾好你的家人
All right, buddy. Sleep well.
行了 睡个好觉
- Good night, Ju-Ju. - Good night.
-晚安 珠珠   -晚安
Okya all clear.
好了 一切都安全了
《Don't Go Away》
Moonbeats and starlight
Jewel：月光和星光
magical Twilight
神奇的曙光
The warmest rain
最温暖的雨
Hear it wispering your names
听他低吟你的名字
Rainbows at midnight
午夜的彩虹
sparkling night sky
让星空闪耀
Don't go away
不要远走
stay another day
多停留一天
Can you sing again please.
你能再唱一遍吗？
Time to bad now.
该睡觉了
What an amazing day.
多棒的一天啊
All this time, I...
一直以来 我...
I never let myself...hope that they were alive but..
我都没奢望过他们还活着
But they are.
但是他们真的还都活着
We found our family Blu
我们找到家人了 布鲁
This changes everything.
这会改变一切的
Yeah.
是的
Wait wait what? What changing?
等等 什么？ 改变什么？
Jewel
珠儿
Go on
去..去 走开
Honey stop. That's tickles.
亲爱的 别 别这样 很痒的
That was fun.
哈哈 真有意思
Tiago!
迪耶戈!
Come on, Tiago! Let's go!
快走 迪耶戈 看我们走
Good morning.
早上好
Or should I say afternoon.
或者我应该说 下午好
Morning sir.
早上好 先生
Our days in jungle is start early.
生活在这里得习惯早起
Good morning, Daddy.
早上好 爸爸
That's my girl see? already up and at'em
真是我的好女儿 她早就起来了
Good morning sweety.
早上好 亲爱的
Why did you let me sleep in?
你干嘛让我睡懒觉
What are you talking about? You sleep in every day.
你说什么呢？你每天都睡懒觉
- Yeah, but... - Hey Dad!
-是的 可是...   -爸爸
Aunt Mimi said plants is good for digestion.
咪咪阿姨说泥土对消化有好处
- Try some. - No,sweety, I just brushed..
-试试啊   -不 宝贝儿 我刚刚刷过牙
Is good, right? I'll go get some more.
味道不错吧 我再去弄点
My girl.
聪明的孩子
So I thought I'd take Stu here for a little tour of the area
我说要领格鲁转一转
Show him around
参观一下
- It's a great idea. - What?
-这主意太好了  -什么？
You go fan with Dad, and I'll take a explore with the kids.
你跟爸爸出去转转 我带孩子们探探险
- Okay, sure. - You'll love it.
-恩 好的   -你会喜欢的
Okay, great. I just get a...
恩 好的  我只要...
Okay  ready.
行了  好了
Okay Blu come closer.
行了 布鲁 靠近点
- Not so close. - Okay.
-太近了   -好的
Listen...
听着...
I can't look at it  You gotta lose that human pocket ok?
我看不下去了 你把人类的口袋扔掉 行吗？
This here is a fanny pack.
这只是个腰包
A fanny pack, amiable.
腰包嘛 很可爱
Is human.
但这是人类的
Now that will join the tribe
现在你已经是部落的一员了
You wouldn't need it any anymore.
你以后用不着它了
I'll meet you by the clay banks
我们在河边泥岸上见
No, wait, join the tribe?
哦 不 加入部落？
He does not actually think we move to the jungle, doesn't he?
他不会以为我们真要搬到丛林里来吧
No, he's just excitied for us here
不 不 他是因为我们来了 太激动了
Let's not spoil the moment ok.
别扫兴好么
Besides, it won't kill you to leave behind the fanny pack
再说了 不带这个腰包去又不会要了你的命
All right, you win.
好吧 你赢了
I leave the fanny pack behand.
我不带腰包就是了
Happy wife happy life.
老婆开心 日子舒心
Bye honey. Have fun.
再见 亲爱的 玩的开心点
Yeah sure. Goodbye.
哦 当然 再见
Guys wakey wakey
各位 该起床了
Wake up!
起床啦！
Eve you got it.
伊娃 你有角色了
What happened on Amazon untapped?
那个野性亚马逊怎么样了？
Here is the plan
我订了计划
Audition today and rehearse the show tomorrow.
今天面试 然后明天预演一场
We, you said we, are you speak French?
我们？什么 你在说法语么？
Come on cha-cha. Let's get started.
行了 赶紧的 我们开始吧
Wow..she is being working.
哇哦 她动作可够快的
Anytime! When ready.
准备好了就可以开始了
每次碰见个男的 我就想把他追到手
可是他们最后都逃走了 我就装傻 我就装酷
管他们想什么 做什么
我不关心 到此结束 (太快了，没听明白....)
- Next! -We are the..
-下一个  -我们是
Amazing capoeiristas turtles.
神奇的巴西战舞龟
Bravo! Another one! Another one!
太精彩了 再来一个 再来一个
Sorry guys! Did I miss something?
抱歉 伙计们 刚才谁表演
Hi my name is Clara, the capybara
嗨 我叫格兰纳 我是水豚
and I'll sing my favorite song.
我要唱一首我最喜欢的歌
Memory
回忆
All I lonely under the moonlight
孤零零的站在月光里
Touch me
告诉我
is so easy to leave me
离开是如此的容易
If you keep eating at there'll get no show.
再这么吃下去我们就没有演员了
It's not your eat competition!
这里不是比谁吃的多！
Oh hey, you're fast. You're really fast
嘿 你飞的好快 真的好快
I think I pulled a wing or something
我觉得我翅膀已经拉伤了
You are really fast for a old bird.
你这老鸟飞的还真快
For such a wise...wise
我是说...你的智慧
Wise bird, a wise bird.
智慧 拥有很多智慧的鸟
Wisdom is which sometimes comes with age
智慧一般是随年龄一起增长的
But also can happen when you're young like you
不过年轻的时候也增长 比如像你
In your case You can be wise and young
又年轻 又智慧
Which is kind of a rare combination.But thrilling when it happens
这种组合很少见 不过看到你真的好让人激动
- Be quiet. - Thank you, sir.
-安静点儿   -哦 谢谢
It's time to take the city of you.
你应该把城市的习惯丢掉了
Need to learn the basics of jungle survival
你要学习基本的...丛林生存要素
I thought we were to go sightseeing
我们不是出来观光的吗？
It's training day.
今天是训练日
Come on! Mud is your friend.
来吧 泥土是你的朋友
She is their camouflage. Feel it, Taste it.
这是你的伪装 感觉他 品尝他
You don't feel tasty, you not doing
如果没感觉 说明你的动作不对
You don't want to be seen by humans.
你不会想被人类看见的
Come on Are you a macaw or turkey?
快点儿 你是蓝皮克斯鹦鹉还是火鸡？
Faster! Faster!
快点 再快点
Come on! You don't want to be eaten.
加油！你不想被吃掉吧
You're alone in jungle.
你独自一人在丛林里
You get caught in trap.
你被陷阱抓住了
What will you do?
你会怎么办？
Well, if I had my fanny pack... -no
-如果我的腰包在的话  -不
- Uses your beak! - My beak!
-你要用你的嘴   -我的嘴？
Your most important tool.
这是你最重要的工具
Okay, I use my beak.
好的 我用我的嘴
- Almost. - Time's up.
-就差一点了   -时间到
You are jaguar's meat.
你挂了
Roberto got first tried.
罗伯特第一次就成功了
Of course he did.
肯定的
Up, Up, plane!
上 上 盘旋
Now Back!
现在倒着飞
Fly back? Only hummingbird can fly backward.
倒飞？什么 不 只有蜂鸟能倒着飞
Backward.
倒着飞
Under! Over! Under! Over!
跳 飞起来 俯冲 在高点
- Good job! - Thanks.
-干得好   -谢谢
Not you
没说你
Brazil nut trees
这是巴西栗树
These trees are the key to our alive
这些树对我们的生存至关重要
The trees feed us they sustain us
这些树为我们提供食物 它们供养我们
They...
他们...
Wake up!
醒醒
I'm up...! Em..nut brazil..
我醒着 我醒着呢 栗巴西还是..
Brazil nut trees something...got it
哦 不 巴西栗树什么的 哦 明白了
This is important.
这很重要
We have to protect these trees.
我们要保护这些树
Our future depends on it.
我们的未来要依靠他们
Edie, who's that sidekick?
嗨 艾迪 这跟班是谁啊
You get a nurses now?
你现在需要护士了？
- Hi, I'm... - - Aren't you boys
-嗨 我是...   -你们是不是
get a little bit too close to our side?
离我们的地盘太近了？
We have an deal, Felipe.
我们说好的 费利佩
Relax! You know you got a old man love for you
嘿 别紧张 你知道我们对你满怀深情
Come on boys  let's fly
来吧 伙计们快飞吧
paint the skies  before they start to cry.
给天空添些色彩吧 让他们去哭鼻子咯
-They seem nice. - They have their side
-他们挺和气的   -树林那边是他们的
and we have ours.
这边是我们的
The food is scarce.
最近食物短缺
I've never seen them so close to the village before.
从没看见他们离我们的家园这么近
- Do not let them see you. - Right right sorry.
-别让他们看到你   -哦 对 抱歉
Maybe we should go find Linda.
也许我们应该去找琳达
- What is Linda? - Linda is the person...
-那是什么？  -琳达是人
- who created me. - What?
-她把我养大   -什么？
-You're the pet? -No no I mean..
-你是宠物？  -不 不..
Is not what you think, I was a companion.
不是你想的那样 我们是朋友
You like it? Oh..
什么？朋友 噢..
That explains everything.
难怪你这幅样子
- Linda's family. - Family?
-琳达是我的家人  -家人？
Humans aren't family.
人类不是我们的家人
You do not understand, they coming here to help.
你没明白 他们是来帮忙的
Listen to me, we do not bring human into the tribe.
听我说 绝对不能带人类来我们的部落
That is only reason we still alive.
远离人类我们才活到现在
You can't be confused about this
这你总应该明白吧
Understand?
你明白了吗？
Yeah. Got it.
是的 明白
Sightseeing is over.
现在 观光结束
Did you see the nest?
你看见鸟巢了嚒？
Tulio are you okay?
图里奥 你没事吧？
Yes, I'm fine i'm ok...
我没事 我很好 我...
I'm not ok.
我不太好
Tulio they're Cutting down the forest!
图里奥 他们在砍伐森林
- Where is it going? - To talk to them.
-琳达你要去哪？  -去和他们说
You talk to birds and I talk to humans.
你去跟鸟说 我去和人说
No wait!
不 等等
Hi hi mister hello
嘿 先生 你好
You can take it easy with that chain saw.
我命令你把电锯关掉
There are rare birds living around here.
有很珍贵的鸟类居住在这片丛林里
You can not cut these trees!
你不能把这些树都砍掉
Oh sweetheart, there you are
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿啊
I was looking for you.
我到处找你
Hello! It's beautiful out here, isn't it?
嗨 你好 这儿真漂亮 对吗？
You two lost?
你们迷路了？
Lost? Not!
迷路？ 没有 呵呵 迷路？
We are here.. have honeymoon.
我们是来 来 来度蜜月的
We're actually just heading back to join the tour
我们正要回去和旅行团汇合呢
Is a karaoke night.
今天晚上 有一场卡拉ok
Come on henny, moonriver isn't going sing a song.
走吧 亲爱的 人家还等着我们去唱..月亮河呢
Linda, woods aren't the only things these guys cut.
琳达 这些人砍得可不止这些树
Run! Run Linda I'll hold them off. Go! Go!
快跑 琳达 我拖住他们 快跑！
Excuse me
请让一下
Come on! Let's Race.
来吧 我们来比赛
- Cool! - All right, Tiago.
-真是太棒了  -好样的 迪耶戈
Tiago!
迪耶戈
Oh that's so good
哦 太爽了
Hey you're back
嘿 你们回来啦
How did it go?
玩儿的怎么样啊？
We had a great time. It was educational.
我们玩的很开心 今天很有教育意义
Dad, Uncle Beto taught me some cool fly tricks.
爸爸 鲍勃叔叔教了我一些很酷的飞行技巧
- Uncle? - Look, I can fly backwards.
-叔叔？  -看 我会倒着飞啦
Yeah you are naturel tree bird.
是啊 你很有天分
It's Never too soon to learn the way in jungle Tiago.
丛林的生活技巧要从小学起
Also someone may never learn.
可是有些家伙学不会
I'm getting go have a.. clean up.
我要去..洗个澡（可怜的blu）
Roberto we saw human near the orchard.
罗伯特 我看见人类在丛林附近
I mean you have to stay aleart.
你要保持警惕
Way lives in jungle...
丛林的生活方法..
I'd better learen go out of the jungle.
我倒想学离开的方法
There he is. Now is our chance.
哦 他在那儿 我们的机会来啦
I'm so excitied!
哦 我真是太激动了
Prepare the tongue-a-bult.
准备舌头弹弓
Charlie, make me fly again.
查理 让我重新飞起来
Get them tiger.
去干掉他们 老虎
Bow before the conquering cockatoo!
快向征服你的凤头鹦鹉跪拜吧
What is your problem, dude?
你是不是有病啊 伙计？
That was sick!
天哪 好变态啊
That's the energy you bring to an audition
我说 面试的时候就该有这种镜头
Audition?
面试？
Yeah,thats actually why I'm here.I've got a greatlittle...
是啊 我就是面试的 我有一个很棒的....
go on.
您继续
We are looking for a new star.
我们在寻找一个新的明星
Star?
明星？
You look familiar.
你看上去很眼熟
Don't I know you from somewhere?
我们是不是哪儿见过？
No, I don't think so
不 不 不会的
I am... Bob.
我叫...鲍勃
Yes Bob the bird..
小鲍勃..
OK. show us what you got
无所谓啦 展示才艺吧
At first, I was afraid
恩 一开始我很害怕
I was petrified.
我惊得目瞪口呆
I kept thinking that I could never live
我一直以为我没法再活下去
I could barely fly.
没法再展翅飞翔
And I spend oh.. so many nights thinking
我在无数个慢慢长夜里回想
how he did me wrong
回想起他对我的残忍
But I grew strong.
于是我变得坚强
And I learned how to get alone
我学会了如何随遇而安
Go on, now go
走吧 快滚
《I Will Survive》
Walk out the door
滚出这扇门
Just turn around now
转身离开吧
It's I who have the floor
现在这里是我的了
was not you who tried hurt me with goodbye
你不就是那个想用分手来伤害我的人吗？
Did you think I'd lay down and die
-你以为我会垮掉  -哦 不
你以为我会躺在这儿死掉？
-Oh, no Nige  -I'll survive
-不 奈杰尔你不会  -我会活下来
As long as I know how to hate, I know I'll stay alive ahh..
只要我知道怎么去恨 我就会活下来
I've got all my life to live
我会好好过这一生
And I got all my love to give
我又满腔的爱要付出
-And I'll survive -You'll survive
-我会活下来  -你会活下来
-And I'll survive  -We'll survive
-我会活下来  -我们会活下来
I'm a survivor, I've got the eye of a tiger
我是个幸存者 我的眼睛虎视眈眈
I've been training again and eating my fiber
加强修炼 多吃高纤
You've been staying alive well I've been staying aliverer
你只是活着 而我是鲜活的活着
Watch where you sit when I spit my saliva like boom
你要坐稳了 我吐口水的时候声音响彻云霄
You've never seen a cockatoo
你从来没见过一只凤头鹦鹉
Rocking shaking and droping and opoing and locking too
随着摇滚的节奏 又唱又跳 尽情摇摆
Watch what I can do without no autotune
看看我的本事 都用不着调音器
Say what?
怎么样
All he did it
真的没有用哦
If you try to keep me down
如果你你打压我
I'll just come back stronger
只会让我变得更坚强
If you try to cut me short
你想打断我
I'll just come back longer
只会让我说的更多
If you beat me at ping pong
如果你想用乒乓球打败我
I'll ust play ping pong-er
我会变成乒乓球健将
Give my my throne, I'm ready to thrive
给我个王位 我准备好上位
I know I'll survive
我很清楚 我会活下去
I will...
我会...
Survive
活下去
Yeah Thank you, I am little Bob the bird
谢谢 我是小鸟 鲍勃
He is so hot.
他真是太帅了
- Yes that's it you're in
-好了 就是他 我要了
- You is not Eve,  but you're awesum.
-虽然不如伊娃 但是你很棒
We'll see you at the performance tomorrow night
明天晚上狂欢节演出的时候见
Everyone from this village is coming
这里所有的鸟都会来看
It's gonna be off the charts
你一定会红到发紫的
Everyone.
所有鸟
Everyone?
Is the perfect plan.
这是个完美的计划
Bless the godden plating you, porcupine.
算你运气好 拔你几根刺 豪猪
Go away.
滚吧
In stead of chasing that bird all over the jungle
与其满林子追那只鸟
We let him come to us at the Carnaval show
不如让他演出的时候自己送上门
I'll mesmerize them from te stage
我会在舞台上迷住他们
While in the audience you my little Gabi
而在观众席里 你 我的小噶比...
You'll be my petite weapon of muss destruction
你会成为我的 迷你致命武器
It will be a performance..
这场演出将会是..
To die for
好看到死
It only works when I do it.
只有我才笑得出那种气场
Okay. Love you.
好的 爱你哦
So minty.
啊...舒服
Yes!
好耶
Hi, sweetheart. here you are. Why is it taking so long?
哦 亲爱的 你在这儿 怎么这么长时间？
Enough with this GPS, seriously!
啊 别再弄那个GPS了
Whole tribe is gathering for sunset come on
我们一起去看日落 快走吧
Hey wait. I just find Linda and Tulio's coordinates.
等一下 我刚找到琳达和图里奥的坐标
They're just on the other side of the orchard, look!
他们就在林子的另一半 瞧
They are very close.
他们离得很近
I know that your father does not totally trust humans
是呀 我知道你爸爸不相信人类
But I'm sure he met them he change his mind
可他一旦见到了 他就会改变想法
They can help to keep this place safe.
琳达他们能保护这里
Yeah Blu, my dad is doing and...
是的 布鲁 我爸自己能解决
Can't you just forget your Linda and tulio one minute?
我说你能不能忘掉琳达和图里奥一会儿？
and enjoy the sunset?
好好享受日落？
But I thought that was our plan.
但是这不是我们的计划吗？
New gide is complete
GPS:路线规划完成
I. ..You know...
恩...我...你知道
Maybe some places should't be found.
有些地方也许不该被发现
Maybe they should be left alone.
也许就应该与世隔绝
She ate a bug! A bug!
她吃了一只虫子 一只虫子
Blu blu bul...calm down!
布鲁 布鲁 冷静
Calm down? We have a plan
冷静？我们有个计划
Help Linda and Tulio find the flocks and get home.
帮助琳达和图里奥找到鹦鹉 然后回家
But I mentioned her she completely shut me down
可是我提醒他 她根本就不理我
Oh..And her father..
哦 还有他的爸爸
Totally a nut job. Has a weird thing about humans.
他就是个疯子 他对人类的看法很奇怪
He's got this weird thing about humans
他对人类的看法很奇怪
He loves them! He is a pet!
他爱人类 他是个宠物
A pet?
宠物？
He called me a pet!
他叫我宠物！
I can't believe he used that word to my face
真不敢相信 他居然当我的面这么说
It's looks like me as the enemys or something!
像是把我当成敌人似的
It is not one of us, Roberto. Keep eyes on him.
他跟我们不是一路的 你要盯着点儿他
And that Roberto He is always watching.
还有那个罗伯特 他在监视
He's always hovering around Jewel He is always singing something
总是在珠儿身边转 总是唱着什么歌
I can't compete with that.
我根本比不上他
You have to be a bird guy! If release of domestication!
你要拿出点鸟样来 从被驯养的状态中解放出来
Try to see this place through her eyes.
用珠儿的眼光看这里
Taste the flavors she's tasting.
去尝尝珠儿品尝的那些味道
So..I should eat a bug?
让我去吃虫子？
This is disgusting think about it.
想想都觉得恶心 在考虑下吧
- Shine! Where is my glitter?
-闪光片 我的闪光片在哪儿？
- Oh Sorry, sorry
-哦 对不起 对不起
I don't want apologize I want glitter
我不需要听道歉 我要闪光片
Brightness is absolutely essential for magic performances.
充满魔力的表演最终要靠的就是闪光片
Do not you know anything?
你怎么就不懂呢？
Guys, rehearsal... big day tomorrow
伙计们 快去彩排 明天是个大日子
Remember about? Come on! You're coming right Dad?
想起来了吗？ 来吧 你来吗 爸爸？
Oh Yes... of course.
哦 当然了
That girl puts the business in show business
那孩子把娱乐搞得像是交作业
- Remember... - I know I know
-布鲁 记住   -我知道 我知道了
Happy wife happy life.
老婆开心 日子舒心
What a glorious morning!
多么美好的晨曦啊！
I forgot I could have a mornings like this.
我都忘记了能够享受这样的早晨
Your favorite.
你最爱吃的
Ao..You remember. Isn't that nice
哦..你记得这个 这真是太好了
It's so crazy good. Thank you so much Blu.
这感觉真是好极了 谢谢你 布鲁
That's it!
对呀
I'll be the one to surprise her breakfast in bed coming up
我要给珠儿一个惊喜 给他送早餐 马上就来
Brazil nuts, where are you?
巴西栗 你们在哪儿？
I know you around here somewhere.
我就知道你们在这附近
No hey hey come back here
不 快回来 等等
- This is not a toy! - Directing dangerous
-那不是玩具  -GPS:违章驾驶 靠边停车
No no don't do it.
不 不 不要
Gotcha!
抓到你了
Finally! Brazil nuts!
总算找到了 巴西栗
This is my most important tool.
这个才是我最重要的工具
Well well well what do we have here
好啊 好啊 瞧瞧这是谁来了
I guess the old Eddie's rules don't apply to everyone
看样子不是所有的鸟都遵守老艾迪的规矩
You are in our side.
这儿是我们的地盘
Really? My bad. Do not know that, sorry.
哦 是吗？ 对不起 我没注意到 真抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
对不起 对不起
You come over here, take our food
闯进我们的地盘 抢我们的食物
and now you insult me?
现在你还侮辱我？
No, no. This is just a big misunderstanding
不 不 不 这件事儿完全是个误会
You know, I wish I could accept your apology
知道吗 我非常想接受你的道歉
You seem like a nice bird
你看上去像是只好鸟
but this means war!
可是这代表战争！
What? Does it have to? Can't it mean something else?
什么？有必要吗？能代表点别的吗？
Today in the pit of doom
今天 在死亡坑
Sorry, the pit of doom really?
对不起 死亡坑 真的吗？
- Oh,really  -highnoon.
-哦 真的 -正午
I'll make some room
我要腾出点地方
Sweep you up like a broom
像扫帚一样把你扫出这片林子
- You did what? - It was an accident.
-你干了什么？   -那是个意外
-An accident? - What's going on?
-意外  -嘿 出了什么事？
Thanks to Stu here,we're going  rights to the rntire grove
多谢布鲁 我们可能要失去这片林子了
I was just trying to get a nut! One nut
我只是想去摘个坚果  就一个
You don't even like nuts,what's gotten in to you Blu?
你都不喜欢吃坚果 这到底是怎么一回事 布鲁？
I want getting it for you
我想给你准备点早餐
Are you were?
哦 真的吗？
Roberto, I want your best birds on it.
罗伯特 你带上最棒的鸟去
We will not give up without a fight!
我们绝不能不战而降
Got it!
明白
You! Stay out of it! Have kitted enough.
你 别管这事儿了 净添麻烦
- Wait! - Blu, he's right.
-等等   -布鲁 他是对的
Maybe you should let dad and Roberto handle it
就让爸爸和罗伯特去处理这件事吧
- You don't think I can do this?
-你也觉得我处理不了？
- Not! I just...
-不 我只是...
Do not know if it's your exactly in expertise
只是不太确定 外交在不在你的专长范围内
Let's go... pit of doom now!
快走  快走 死亡坑
Radio
无线电！
I hope you do not mind  I make myself at home
我希望你别介意 我把这儿当自己家
A lollipop?
棒棒糖？
Is a shame. You all came this way to protect the jungle.
真是可惜啊 你们两位大老远跑来保护这片森林
Let's see if she returns the favor.
我们看看它会不会报答你们
Tree huggers...
两个疯子...
- Roberto... - Felipe...
-罗伯特   -费利佩
No mercy!
给他点厉害瞧瞧
- I have to stop this. - What? Blu!
-我得阻止他们  -什么 布鲁？
Stop, stop! Edwardo this is crazy.
停下 停下 艾迪 这太疯狂
We are intelligent species
我们是高等物种
with advanced problem solving techniques.
我们能更好的解决问题
You brought this on us! Now watch.
这是你挑起来的 等着瞧吧
- Head. - Tails.
- 头冲上  -尾巴冲上
I hate this job.
我讨厌这工作
- Oh, it's a game! it's a game!
-这是比赛？ 这是比赛！
- It's not a game It's war.
-这不是比赛 这是战争
It's a beautiful day in the pit of doom!
嘿 嘿 嘿 今天死亡坑天气不错
- It's winner take all! - It's the best of seven.
-这是胜者为王的比赛  -七局四胜
The winner will take control of the entire Brazil nut grove.
获胜者将得到整片巴西栗子林
It's just like soccer. I can do this.
这就像足球 这我会玩
All right. Any special strategies? Will we be running at 4-4-2 or 5-4-1?
有什么特别的战术吗？4-4-2 还是 5-4-1
What are we doing here, coach? What position is likely?
怎么踢 教练 我踢什么位置
Actually I do have a perfect spot for you.
事实上我给你准备了一个合适的位置
Water. Water here. Get your water.
水 这儿有水 来喝水吧
Okay, thanks.
好的 谢谢
Roberto is unstoppable! He's incredible!
罗伯特 他所向披靡势不可挡 到处都是他的身影
- Go, Roberto! - I could have done that.
-加油罗伯特  -哼 这我也能行
Roberto's breaking! There he go!There he go!
罗伯特和对手保持距离 他正在向前冲 向前冲
He shooted!
他射门了！
Goal!
进啦！
Felipe has the ball! The red macaws are making a comeback!
哦 费利佩抢到了球 红金刚鹦鹉要扭转局面
Felipe pass to Tito, Tito to Mario.
费利佩传给提科 提科传给马里奥
Mario to Keita, Keita to Antonio.
马里奥传给凯撒 凯撒传给安东尼
It's goal!
安东尼射门得分！
Yes! In your face!
嘿 去你的吧
Felipe, Roberto, Roberto, Felipe, Felipe...
费利佩 罗伯特 费利佩 罗伯特...
Goal!
射门
- I guess this is gonna hurt. - Go go!
-这一定很疼  -上 上
Felipe! Lipe, Lipe, Lipe!
费利佩 利佩 利佩
-Foul   -Come on Referee
-犯规   -嘿 得了吧 裁判
- Okay. You are in. - Really?
-好吧 你上  -真的？
Not you. You!
没说你 你
Watch and learn waterboy!
学着点吧 送水小子
- All right. Get in there. - Yes!
-好吧  你..你上吧  -好的
Here, here we go.
开始吧 教练
Yeah, Dad!
嘿 爸爸
A new player is coming off the bench! Is he a secret weapon?
现在有位替补队员上场了 他会是秘密武器吗？
I think he's the waterboy.
他不就是那个送水的吗
Hey! I'm open! I'm open! Toss it to me!
没人防我  没人防我 把球传给我啊
Pass to me! I'm open. I am wide open!
传给我 我这儿没人防守 快传给我啊
Pass the ball to me!
把球传给我
- Thanks for the pass, Blu!
-谢谢你把球传给我
- Might I borrow this?
-借用一下
Roberto looked this. He shied a defense, another!
罗伯特向前挺进 他避开一个防守 又避开一个
Roberto! Goal!
罗伯特 进啦
We are tie now at the pit of doom.
目前的比分 3比3
Whoever scores next... - Wins all!
接下来谁先进球 谁就赢得比赛
Oh! I got it, I got it!
我来接 我来接
Come on, Blu.
加油 布鲁
Wow! The water boy suddenly playing like a pro!
哇噢 送水小子突然表现出了专业水准
Pass the ball to Roberto!
把球传给罗伯特
Pass the ball! Pass the ball!
快传球  快传球！
- Blu, wait! - This bird's gonna covered!
-布鲁 等等  -我自己能搞定
It looks like the secret weapon lost its fire.
看上去这个秘密武器 突然走火了
Let's go to Edwardo for his reaction.
我们来看看艾迪现在的反应
I'm gonna kill you fanny pack!
我要杀了这只该死的宠物
Check it out, old Eddie.
哦 老艾迪
Looks like you guys are gonna have to start a nut-free diet!
看样子你们没有坚果吃了 只能减肥了
We'll be talking about that for a long time.
这场比赛在我们那儿会传为佳话的
I should have never expected more of a human's pet.
我真不该对人类的宠物报抱什么希望
What happened back there?
嘿 刚才你怎么回事儿啊？
I was trying to be one of the tribe.
我太想融入这个大家庭了
But I guess I'm never gonna be the bird like your dad wants me to be.
但我可能永远都不能成为你爸爸希望的那样
- My... what? - I think it's time to go home.
-你..说什么？   -我想我们该回家了
- We should talk about this. - Talk about what?
-我正要跟你说呢   -跟我说什么？
Blu, look around.
布鲁 看看周围
The kids are thriving. They love being in the wild.
孩子们这里 在野外玩的这么的开心
Maybe this place is home.
也许这里就是我们的家
Home? How can this be home?
我们的家？ 这里是我们的家？
I've done everything I can to fit in and help out
我尽全力适应这里 帮助他们
but no matter what I do it's wrong!
可我做什么都不对
That's not home, Jewel.
这不是我们的家 珠儿
Maybe for you, but not for me.
也许属于你 但不是我的
You know what? You need to figure out what you want.
知道吗？ 你应该清楚你到底需要什么
And maybe
而且
Stop thinking about just yourself and start thinking about us.
别老想着你自己 也为我们想想吧
Move out! Let's go.
出发 出发 快点
Beautiful.
太好了
Linda! Tulio!
琳达 图里奥
Goodbye  Linda.
再见 琳达
- Goodbye, fanny pack
-再见 小腰包
Turn around when possible.
请在能拐弯的时候拐弯
Sorry, GPS lady. It's not you it's...it's me.
抱歉 GPS小姐 不是你的错 是我的不对
Goodbye, pancakes. Goodbye, coffee.
再见 煎饼 再见 咖啡
Goodbye coffee.
再见 咖啡
Linda?
琳达？
Linda!
琳达
Edwardo was right! Traitor!
艾迪说的对  你是个叛徒
- Wait. You don't understand.
-等等 你不明白？
- What don't I understand? Siding with humans?
-我有什么不明白的 与人类为伍？
- What do you even know about humans?
-你对人类了解多少？
- Oh I know everything.
-哦 我很了解他们
They lure you in! They trap you!
他们引诱你 把你抓起来
They destroy your mind!
他们还给你洗脑！
Polly want a cracker? Polly want a cracker?
鹦鹉要吃饼干吗 要吃饼干吗？
No! Enough crackers! I hate crackers.
不 我受够饼干了 我讨厌饼干
- Come on, Roberto!
-快走 罗伯特
- It's them! It's them! It's them!
-是他们 是他们 是他们！
Roberto, get out of there!
让开
Not again, not again! No more crackers!
不要 不要 我不要饼干
Stop out of it!
你冷静点
Look, we got one chance to stop this, okay?
听好 我们还有个机会阻止这一切
I have to find my friends.
我去找到我的朋友
You fly back and warn the others, you got it?
你飞回去警告大家 明光吗？
- Yeah, I got it. - Okay! Go! - Okay!
-明白   -好的 快去！
Humans! Humans!
人类 人类！
- Your left! Right! - Left or right?
-往你的左边 不右边 右边  -左还是右？
Your right leg my left leg.
你的右腿 我的左腿
- Good good.
好的 就这样
Now go..up up.
现在..往上爬  爬!
Reach. Almost there!
差一点了 就快到了
Linda I'm so sorry.
琳达 我真的很抱歉
As bad as this is, there is no place...
虽然情况很糟糕 但是我全世界哪儿也不想去
I would rather be in the whole world than with you
只想和你在一起
Even it's tie to a tree
哪怕是被拴在一棵树上 (记得 第一部里Jewel和blu吗?)
oh Linda
哦 琳达~
Blu! Blu!
布鲁 布鲁
- Linda? - Down here!
-琳达？   -下面！
- What? Blu! - What are you doing here?
-啊 布鲁  -你怎么在这儿？
This is dangerous.
这里很危险
That's incredible! It's a 2000-mile flight!
真难以置信 里约飞到这儿有2000英里
Let's follow him!
-我们跟着他  -太神奇了
I told you I heard him!
我就说我听到他的声音了
blu: Let me take those.
还给我钥匙
ps：好有Avatar的感觉
It's over! Humans! The light! The light!
一切都完了 人类 人类
The light...No...
那些光 那些光 不...
He's been staggering like this since we found him.
自从我们找到他 他就不停的说胡话
The loggers are coming and Blu is with them.
伐木工来了 布鲁和他们在一起
- Traitor!s.
-他是个叛徒
- No, Blu is trying to help us.
-不 布鲁是想帮我们
- What? By himself? - Let's evacuate!
什么？ 就他自己？  -我们快撤
We are leaving. Let's go, everyone move out! Go! Go! Go!
离开这里 所有的鸟立刻出发 快 快 快
Dad, no, not this time. I'm not going with you.
爸爸 这次不行 我不能和你一起走
You have to go with me
你必须和我一起走
I will not put my family in danger again.
我不能再让家人面临危险
Blu is my family and I'm not leaving him behind.
布鲁也是我的家人 我不会丢下他的
You don't have to.
不用担心
Are you okay?
你没事吧
Look, Edwardo, I might not be the birdiest bird in the flock.
听着 埃德沃德 也许我不是这里最有鸟样的鸟
But for once that's actually a good thing.
就现在来说 这是好事
You know the jungle, I know humans.
你了解丛林 我了解人类
And I know that together we can stop them.
我们合作就能阻止伐木工
We can't let them take our home.
不能让他们夺走我们的家园
Sure it's hot, and loud and filled of creepy bugs.
虽然这里又热又吵 到处是恐怖的虫子
But it's ours. Let's fight for it!
可这是属于我们的 我们要为他而战
- Who is with me? - I'm with you!
-谁跟我去？  -我跟你...
Anybody else?
还有谁吗？
Stop! Stop! Stop!
停下 停下
Stop!
停下！
Oh yeah! Respect the rainforest!
哦 这就对了 请尊重热带雨林
I knew it! I knew it! I knew...
我就知道  我就知道 我就...
Where do you think you're going?
你这是要去哪儿？
It's just a bunch of pigeons.
那只不过是一群该死的鸽子
Get back to work!
给我回去干活
Lead the way  Blu.
你带头 布鲁
That's my name, yes. You called me Blu!
终于叫对了 你叫我布鲁
Yes! I am Blu.
对 我叫布鲁！
What? Oh, oh, right. Birds of blue feathers...
哦 哦 对 有蓝色羽毛的鸟
have to stick together!
团结在一起
Everybody ready? And under!
准备好了吗？ 现在往下
Over!
往上
Backwards!
倒飞！
I'll survive, I will survive.
我会活下去 我会活下去
- Got it! - Wow, precise.
-抓到了   -哇 好准
I'm afraid of no birds.
我才不怕什么鸟呢
Attack!
进攻
- It's on in the Amazon.
-亚马逊保卫战开始了
- All right, hit it!
-准备 扔
High-five!
击掌
- Why? Why? - Get hold of youelf!
-为什么？为什么？   -给我振作起来
Incoming!
炮弹来了
There he is. Charlie, prepare the nozooka!
停下 他在那儿 查理 给我准备鼻射炮
- Tiago. - That's what I were talking.
-迪耶戈   -这才对嘛
Ready, aim, fire!
准备 瞄准 开火
Foiled again.
又失手了
- Good job, Tiago! - We are great team, Dad!
-干得好 迪耶戈  -我们是最棒的团队
- Felipe? - You think I'd miss this party?
-费利佩? -你以为我会错过这个机会？
Game on!
比赛开始
Hey! Come back! You are useless! All of you!
嘿 快回来 一群饭桶 没用的东西
Look out!
小心
Pick on someone your own size!
要打架 找个个子和你一样大的
- No! No! - Gotcha, gotcha.
-不 不  -接住你了 接住你了
It's Okay, it's okay, you are safe now.
别害怕 没事了 你安全了
That's a Linda.
那就是琳达
We stil got it, Blu.
还是这么默契 布鲁
I have to do everything myself.
真是的 什么事都得我亲自干
- Hey! Get away from that!
-给我滚开
- No way, no one steals my scene.
-不 没有人可以抢我的戏
Lollipop?
棒棒糖？
What?
什么？
What are you doing? Let go, save yourself.
你在干嘛？ 快走 快逃命吧
- Come on, let go. - Never.
-快放开  -我就不
Are you crazy? You are bringing both of us down! Let go!
你疯了吗？ 你会把我们两个都害死的
- Deja vu, Blu. - Nigel!
-飞呀 似曾相识吧 布鲁  -奈杰尔
- Blu!  - Nigel!
-布鲁  -奈杰
You!
你
You'll pay it, pay the price for your insolence!
你要为你的罪恶付出最惨痛的代价
Stop it. Get away from here.
住手 别过来
Give my furious feathers in your face.
用我愤怒的羽毛 扇肿你的脸
- You don't have to do this.
-你没必要 没必要这么做
- Oh, I just want to.
-我就是想这么做
Oh my God! Charlie! This is it, this is it!
哦天哪 查理 机会来了
Steady, steady.
稳住 稳住
Slap fight!
扇耳光比赛
Shoot! Shoot!
就是现在 发射！
Oh! Nigel!
哦 奈杰尔
Is this the end?
我就要死了吗？
I was too young, too beautiful to live.
我太年轻 又太英俊 天妒英才
- Bob? - Hold up, that ain't Bob!
-鲍勃  -等下 那不是鲍勃
I told you I knew him from somewhere.
我就说我见过他
My final curtain call
这是我最后的谢幕
has standing room only.
现在只剩下站票了
Goodbye.
再见
No! No! What have I done?
不！！我干了些什么啊
If you can not live it with me then I shall not live it at all.
如果不能与汝同生 那我不如死了算了
That frog is not poisonous.
那只青蛙它没有毒
- What? - We're not dead?
-什么？  -我们没有死？
It's a very common mistake.
这个品种经常被搞错
But she's a colostethus Dendrobate.
它是只假的箭毒蛙
You can tell by the pink spots.
从它粉色的斑点就能看出来
But my parents always told me I was poisonous
可我父母从小告诉我说 我有剧毒
and shouldn't touch anyone.
叫我别碰任何人
You just have really mean parents.
你是你爹妈充话费送的吧？
So now...We can be together!
那么现在 我们可以在一起啦
- Nigel! Nigel! - No! No! My victory help me!
-奈杰尔 奈杰尔 我的维克多  -谁来救救我
- I will never let you go! - I'm sorry, I'll be nicer.
-我绝对不会放你走的  -不 不 我会学好的
No! No! Charlie!
不 不 查理
Charlie!
查理
This is unatural!
这是违反自然法则的
嘿 伙计们 嗨 头发没弄脏吧 Hi, guys， hi. There's nothing in my hair, right?
Directly from the heart of the Amazon rainforest
我们从亚马逊的腹地
we have some breaking news.
为你带来特大新闻
Thanks to Dr. Monteiro and his team
多亏了图里奥博士和他的团队
the entire area will be designated
这里的整片区域都将会制定为
as a national wildlife refuge
国家野生鸟类保护区
and together we will make sure this place stay safe.
我们大家会一起确保这里的安全
Right, Blu?
对吗 布鲁？
But that's not the only good news.
好消息还不止这一个
We found this cockatoo deep in the Amazon
我们在丛林深处找到这只凤头鹦鹉
and he seems to have bounded to a tree frog
他好像和一只树蛙黏在一起
We are bringing them back to Rio
我们会把它带回里约
for continuing observation.
进行持续的观察
Oh, Nigel, wow! A honeymoon in Rio!
哦 奈杰尔 我们要去里约度蜜月啦
Put paws, downs, and tails together
大家一起来 拍手 拍手 摇尾巴
for the most amazing talents ever gathered in one jungle!
这是丛林里有史以来最强大的明星阵容
It's Amazon untamed!
下面请看--野性亚马逊
《 Batucada Familia》
What's up? Don't Bite it. What's up? Don't Bite it
嘿 嘿 别咬我 别咬我
Where are my birds up?
我的鸟儿朋友们
Flap your wings.
翅膀挥舞起来
Amazon.
亚马逊
It's an emerald we treasure
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
Coming from the jungle to you
从密林来到你的面前
Beating like it's hopping.
拍打的是心跳的节奏
Interpretation of the freely notes
演绎的是自由的音符
It's the emerald we treasure
这是我们最爱的绿宝石
- Coming from the place where we live. - Place where we live.
来自我们生活的地方
...happy night
充满着自由和欢乐
Time Flies Past as the breeze
时光不停飞逝
丛林就像一阵清风 一个奇迹
快穿上舞裙 随时有人叫你跳舞 (还是没听清..)
Hello  Amazon!
你好 亚马逊
- Luiz! - Hey birds, I made it!
-嘿 路易兹   -嘿 小鸟们 我来了
Welcome to the Amazon!
欢迎来到丛林
硬汉乌龟
Sing it baby.
唱吧 宝贝儿
Are you sure you can make the Amazon our home?
你确定要在亚马逊安家吗？
- With the heat, the creepy bugs? - What, are you kidding?
-这里有热又有恐怖的虫子  -开什么玩笑
I'm Mr.jungle totally wild and very birdy.
我可是丛林先生 充满野性而且还很有鸟样
Maybe we can beat summer in Rio.
夏天还是去里约避暑吧
You are my one of my only Jewel.
你是我的唯一 珠儿
Ao...
噢...
That's the end?
结束了吗？
《Rio Rio (feat. B.o.B)》